One duty. One desire. One decision.
The Exception is a war, drama, romance film directed by David Leveaux.
Nothing is as it seems in this riveting World War 2 thriller as a wary soldier goes to investigate a mysterious German monarch
at his secluded mansion, leading him into a web of deceit and a dangerous love affair with a local Jewish woman.
Mieke de Jong, played by Lily James.
Capt Stefan Brandt, played by Jai Courtney.
Heinrich Himmler, played by Eddie Marsan.
Kaiser Wilhelm II, played by Christopher Plummer.
Princess Hermine 'Hermo' Reuss of Greiz, played by Janet McTeer.
Secretary, played by Daisy Boulton.
The Exception is a 2016 romantic war film directed by David Leveaux (in his directorial debut) and
written by Simon Burke, based on Alan Judd's 2003 novel The Kaiser's Last Kiss.
The film stars Jai Courtney, Lily James, Janet McTeer, and Christopher Plummer.
The plot is a fictionalized account of the life of
exiled Kaiser Wilhelm II (Plummer).
When a Wehrmacht officer (Courtney) is ordered to determine whether or not a British spy has infiltrated the Kaiser's residence with a
view to assassinating the deposed monarch, he falls in love with one of the Kaiser's maids (James) during his investigation.
The film is set in the occupied Netherlands during World War II.
In 2014, Egoli Tossell Film announced that development on a
film adaptation of Judd's novel had begun.
Principal photography in Belgium lasted six weeks in 2015.
The film held its world premiere at the 2016 Toronto International
Film Festival in the Special Presentations section.
The film received a limited theatrical release and a video-on-demand release on 2
June 2017, through A24 and DirecTV Cinema in the United States.
The film was released on 2 October 2017 in the United
Kingdom through Signature Entertainment.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
nazi, world war i, resistance, spy.
The tone is emotional.